Inspired by a true love story.
The Great Escaper is a history, drama, war film directed by Oliver Parker.
In the summer of 2014, a World War II veteran sneaks out of his care home to attend
the 70th anniversary commemoration of the D-Day landings in Normandy.
Bernard Jordan, played by Michael Caine.
Irene Jordan, played by Glenda Jackson.
Arthur, played by John Standing.
Young Bernard, played by Will Fletcher.
Young Irene, played by Laura Marcus.
Scott, played by Victor Oshin.
The Great Escaper is a 2023 British biographical comedy-drama film directed by Oliver
Parker, written by William Ivory, and starring Michael Caine and Glenda Jackson.
It is based on the true story of 90-year-old  British World War II Royal Navy veteran Bernard Jordan who "broke
out" of his nursing home to attend the 70th anniversary D-Day commemorations in France in June 2014.
The Great Escaper had its world premiere in London at BFI Southbank on 20 September 2023,
and was released in the United Kingdom on 6 October 2023, by Warner Bros.
The film marked the final performance for Jackson, who died in
June 2023, nine months after filming finished.
Caine announced his retirement from acting in October 2023.
This is also the last film produced by Pathé UK, after the division announced  in November 2023 that they would
restructure to focus on premium television and only release films from their parent company.
Another film, The Last Rifleman starring Pierce Brosnan and released on
5 November 2023, is loosely based on Jordan's story.
The tone is emotional.